Louis Young

Front-end Software Engineer [Web | Mobile]

Rue du Maupas 33, Lausanne, Switzerland louisyoung420@gmail.com +41 225480193

A front-end software engineer with a broad knowledge of **JavaScript** technologies and a creative **UI/UX** sense.

My career started in web development after graduating from university in 2015. Since then, I have been working on **front-end** programming for web and mobile applications for over **7 years** specializing in reactive JavaScript technologies, exclusively using **React** and **Vue.js**.

As an accomplished professional in the field of **mobile app** development, I have a strong preference for utilizing **lonic Framework**. My skill set includes full-stack development, with a focus on utilizing **Node.js** and **Laravel** as backend technologies.

I have a passion for crafting **user-friendly interface** and optimizing its **performance**. I maintain a **detail-oriented** and conscientious approach to my work, ensuring a high standard of **quality assurance**.

For more information: https://louisvoung.vercel.app

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP
- ❖ TailwindCSS, Chakra UI, Material UI, Bootstrap, Styled Components
- React, Vue.js, Svelte, Remix, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Gatsby, Inertia.js
- Redux, React Query, Mobx, Zustand, Pinia, GraphQL, Web3, Ether.js, D3
- Ionic, Capacitor, Electron.js
- Jest, Testing Library, Cypress
- PWA, SEO, SSR, SSG
- Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Laravel, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Git, Agile/Scrum, Code review

EXPERIENCE



Meettrax, United States - Front-end Web & Mobile Engineer

NOVEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Vue | Inertia | TypeScript | Pinia | Ionic | Capacitor | Laravel | MySQL | Redis | Pusher | TailwindCSS | PWA | Electron

https://meettrax.com/

- Was responsible for rewriting legacy endpoints, controllers, views to make seemless client-server communication with Inertia.js
- Used optimistic update strategy for all Pinia mutations to provide lightning fast request feedback to users
- Adopted customized caching strategy with Pinia store
- Built meettrax mobile app from prototype to deployment as a sole developer
- Composed mobile UI components crafted from Ionic and TailwindCSS
- Built utility functions for global use using Ionic APIs
- Established real-time communication via Pusher connection



Zebedee, United States - Front-end Web & Mobile Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2022

React | React Native | TypeScript | Redux | Jest | Mixpanel

https://zebedee.io/app

https://zebedee.io/developers/dashboard

- Refactored entire CSS code with styled-components to implement complex dynamic UI elements
- Developed core functionalities such as bitcoin lightning invoicing
- Simplified codebase and improved productivity for future development by swapping legacy Redux store for ReduxToolkit
- Owned product analytics feature utilizing Mixpanel
- Composed unit testing code with React Testing Library and Jest



Blocket AB, Sweden - Full-stack Web & Mobile Engineer

FEBRUARY 2019 - JULY 2021

React | TypeScript | Next.js | Ionic | Capacitor | MaterialUI | GraphQL | Express | Prisma | PostgreSQL | Socket.io | Cypress

https://www.blocket.se

https://www.blocket.se/om/blocket-mobil-app

- Refreshed UI with new Figma design for both web and mobile utilizing MaterialUI

- Optimized performance by minimizing payload, code-splitting, lazy-loading, memoization/caching, and image optimization
- Spearheaded mobile app development with Ionic, React, Capacitor
- API integration and state management using GraphQL Apollo
- Developed GraphQL schema, queries, and mutations in the early stages of backend
- Automated real-time notification with Socket.io in Node.js backend
- Implemented e2e testing with Cypress.io



Pyszne Food Tech, Poland - Freelance Mobile Developer

DECEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Vue | Ionic | Cordova | TypeScript | Pinia | TailwindCSS | D3

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pyszne-pl/id1039818673

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yourdelivery.pyszne&hl=en&gl=US

- Translated design team's UI/UX wireframes and mockups with TailwindCSS into well-organized and component-driven code
- Implemented core modules while closely working with QA team and promptly reflecting feedbacks from various clients and business objectives
- Rewrote all Pinia-based state management code with Vuex to utilize Vuex caching
- Strategically migrated legacy JavaScript codebase to TypeScript
- Data visualiazation with D3



FlorAccess, Netherlands - Freelance Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

Vue | Vuex | Vuetify | ElasticSearch | Stripe | Node.js | MongoDB

https://www.floraccess.com/en/

- Translated approved designs into a fully functional website with Vuetify and Vuex store.
- Integrated Stripe's checkout platform to facilitate secure payments for customers.
- Built API endpoints with Node.js, MongoDB, and mongoose to enhance platform flexibility.
- Accelerated search speed and capabilities by integrating ElasticSearch into the application.



Michael Hill Jeweller, Australia - Freelance Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2015 - OCTOBER 2016

React | Next.js | Redux | Bootstrap| Laravel | MySQL | CRM

https://www.michaelhill.com.au/

- Applied server-side rendering and static side generation and increased SEO with Next.js
- Modularized components and reorganized Redux store by modules

- Developed CRM dashboard for data analysis and visualization (jQuery, Chart.js, Google Map)
- Collaborated closely with backend devs to improve MySQL query efficiency

EDUCATION



Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

Bachelor of science (BS), Computer science SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2015